<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Viktor Barzin (Viktor Barzin&#39;s Website)</title>
    <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Viktor Barzin (Viktor Barzin&#39;s Website)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 10:19:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://viktorbarzin.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>16 SSH Forwarding Quirks</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/16-ssh-forwarding-quirks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 10:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/16-ssh-forwarding-quirks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction SSH is a ubiquitous protocol for managing remote machines securely.
Most of the time one would need just shell access to a remote machine to run commands, however, SSH allows for so much more. One of the interesting features is SSH forwarding - you can forward ports, unix sockets, X11 sessions and other interesting stuff.
All of this is fine until you start sharing the ssh server host with other people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 Arpspoofing Exploitation, Detection and Prevention</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/15-arpspoofing-exploitation-detection-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 17:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/15-arpspoofing-exploitation-detection-prevention/</guid>
      <description>Introduction ARP spoofing is a rather nasty network attack which is not very popular because the attacker needs to be on the same LAN as the victim. This is impractical in most cases, however, if that happens to be the case, a malicious user can easily perform attacks such as Man-In-The-Middled(MitM) and/or Denied of Service(DoS).
Recently I have been working on creating a attack-defense style CTF environment and ARP spoofing in the challenge network is definitely a concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14 DNS Over HTTPS</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/14-dns-over-https/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 09:40:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/14-dns-over-https/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is mainly about me sharing some very useful resources and bringing light onto the cool idea behind DNS-over-HTTPS (aka. DoH).
I&amp;rsquo;ll also share a simple setup on how to run your own DoH server to hide your DNS lookups from spying eyes.
What is DNS-over-HTTPS and why do I need it? As you know, DNS is a rather simple protocol, used for resolving domain names to IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 Client Side Certificate Authentication With Nginx</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/13-client-side-certificate-authentication-with-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 16:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/13-client-side-certificate-authentication-with-nginx/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Authentication is hard. Application-level authentication is even tougher and most of the time, when prototyping something, people (unfortunately) don&amp;rsquo;t think about security and leave wide-open apps listening on the internet.
A simple solution to that could be to use the production web server as an authentication entity that decides whether or not you are allowed to view the upstream application. Both apache and nginx support basic authentication which is essentially a header that your client sends with each request that has your username and password for the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Why I switched from LVM&#43;EXT4 to BTRFS</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/12-why-i-switched-from-lvm-ext4-to-btrfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 01:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/12-why-i-switched-from-lvm-ext4-to-btrfs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Happy 2020 chaps!
It&amp;rsquo;s January again, and it&amp;rsquo;s exam time for me, which means procrastination. And what better way to procrastinate than exploring something awesome like BTRFS snapshots?
In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll share why I migrated from LVM + EXT4 to BTRFS and the benefits I found. I&amp;rsquo;ll go briefly through my experience with BTRFS and I&amp;rsquo;ll also share a tool I found recently - Snapper - which makes snapshotting even easier so let&amp;rsquo;s get started!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 Booting Into Trouble - Learning the differences between MBR/GPT, BIOS/UEFI the hard way</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/11-booting-into-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 12:07:50 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/11-booting-into-trouble/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently I replaced my ancient laptop with a new, slightly better one. People associate changing workstations with OS reinstall, setting up everything from scratch etc.
I&amp;rsquo;d rather put my old disk in my new machine and continue as is. However, due to the age of my old laptop, I had formatted the disk with a Master Boot Record (MBR) and used Legacy Boot mode, which turned out, is not supported on new DELL laptops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Now you see me...</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/10-now-you-see-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 14:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/10-now-you-see-me/</guid>
      <description>Pre-Intro It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since my last blog post.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been quite busy recently, playing around with Go, Haskell, Alex parser, Lex lexer, home-made Rubber Duckies and plenty of other interesting stuff I may blog about at some point.
Introduction This post is about setting up a home face recognition system using an IP Camera, OpenCV and a raspberry pi.
I won&amp;rsquo;t focus on the face recognition part that much since the code I used was not written by me but instead was sourced from this awesome blog post that I highly recommend reading if you&amp;rsquo;re into ML with python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 14:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/donate/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for coming here! If you fancy helping out, hopefully there will be an ad below that you can click.
 
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});  Cheers! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Peeling the layers of security with Security Onion</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/09-peeling-the-layers-of-security-with-security-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 10:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/09-peeling-the-layers-of-security-with-security-onion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This time round, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my experience with Security Onion and the journey of setting it up in my environment.
I will skip the dull installation process (everyone can click next at the prompts) and rather show you how it fits in my increasingly complex network topology. The focus of this blogpost will be on the interconnection between pfSense, VMWare ESXi and Security Onion.
Prerequisites Before reading further on, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend familiarizing yourself with pfSense and the awesome stuff it can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Defeating Censorship And Improving Security With OpenVPN</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/08-defeating-censorship-with-tcp-openvpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 10:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/08-defeating-censorship-with-tcp-openvpn/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I do happen to travel from time to time and in order to stay online I have to use insecure public wifi. Everyone who understands a bit about network security knows the risks of connecting to unsafe networks and how dangerous they could be.
One of the most common solutions to this problem, including mine, is a VPN service. That&amp;rsquo;s all great, however, more and more network administrators put effort into blocking VPN traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Going musical - Setting up an improvised home audio system</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/07-raspberry-bluetooth-aux-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/07-raspberry-bluetooth-aux-setup/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Some time ago myself and a friend of mine won these awesome bluetooth Logitech speakers
The sound is quite decent, unfortunately connecting to both at the same time is a bit tricky and without having an external bluetooth adapter one could not easily play the same music on both.
In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how with a raspberry pi, some clever thinking and a fair amount of patience I managed to stream music simultaneously onto both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 In the big 4! - Facebook Application Experience</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/06-facebook-application-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 19:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/06-facebook-application-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last post. This was due to the fact I was preparing for my interview for Facebook&amp;rsquo;s 2019 Production Engineering Internship Program as well as doing some uni related work which is not really worth blogging about.
Anyway, the good news is that I got that offer from Facebook! I decided this post to be about my overall experience so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for technical post, come back next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 HA!Proxy - Discovering the wonders of proxying and load balancing</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/05-haproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 14:04:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/05-haproxy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this week&amp;rsquo;s post I&amp;rsquo;ll share my experince with HAProxy - a high performance TCP/HTTP load balancer
Disclaimer: There will be nothing that you can&amp;rsquo;t read in the haproxy options manual apart from my thoughts. Still, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in my experience configuring this application for my setup keep on reading.
This post will be shorter than usual because I am a bit low on time since I&amp;rsquo;m preparing for an important interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Down the Rabbit Hole - How a simple monitoring task lead me to compiling a custom version of OpenWRT</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/04-down-the-rabbit-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 10:04:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/04-down-the-rabbit-hole/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this blogpost I&amp;rsquo;ll go through the journey I went when I was setting up monitoring with ELK for my website. The task seemed simple - install *beats and tell it to report to my elk stack vm. You&amp;rsquo;ll see why in my setup it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as easy as it sounds initially.
The issue If you recall my network setup had a little issue - I do not own the public IP address where my infrastructure sits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 A Walk Down Infrastructure Lane - My Home Lab Setup</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/03-a-walk-down-infrastructure-lane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 15:36:21 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/03-a-walk-down-infrastructure-lane/</guid>
      <description>Intro As the tittle suggests It&amp;rsquo;s time to go down infrastructure lane. In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll show my &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; lab and all the services I&amp;rsquo;ve built so far.
I will do my best to keep this up to date so check this post regularly for updates, both to the content and the image at the end.
If you are interested in just the network topology, you can find it here Without further due let&amp;rsquo;s get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Blog a Blog - The creation of this site</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/02-blog-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 15:36:49 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/02-blog-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>Intro Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been quite busy. I was helping with the organisation of HackConf this weekend which was both awesome and exhausting.
Therefore this blog will be covering something simpler - how I created this site. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover the ceation of the actual ui - it is a statically generated website from markdown files (you can find the sources here).
Just google for a static site generator and you&amp;rsquo;ll find plenty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Secure by default - Why you shouldn&#39;t disable Django&#39;s CSRF middleware</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/01-secure-by-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 13:44:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/blog/01-secure-by-default/</guid>
      <description>Brief intro Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around with various client-side web attacks. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that most web devs&#39; knowledge goes as far as the framework their using requires and that&amp;rsquo;s it. When asked what is the purpose of a csrf token, they would say - &amp;ldquo;Oh, it&amp;rsquo;s something for security and if I don&amp;rsquo;t put it, my forms don&amp;rsquo;t work so it must be there.&amp;rdquo;
If you find yourself having a similar answer, keep on reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://viktorbarzin.me/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:22:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://viktorbarzin.me/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! I&amp;rsquo;m Viktor.
I&amp;rsquo;m {{ whatever year we are currently }} - 1998 years old and I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing my BSc in Computer Science at the University of Southampton.
You can find me on facebook, github, linkedin and twitter.
I&amp;rsquo;m all into information security. I love solving interesting and challenging problems and I also enjoy helping others learn new stuff.
In my free time I watch Formula 1, play chess, go and soon I&amp;rsquo;ll be jumping out of planes</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
